# **Ernest D. Peterson**

Web Developer

Pensacola, FL Phone: 601-307-4377 Email Website GitHub LinkedIn

My creative nature and my love for technology has lead me to switch careers. My experiences from starting my own business and managing loads, equipment and personnel gives me a good foundation for teamwork and web development.

### **Skills**

HTML 5 | Javascript/Jquery | CSS 3 | Sass | Git | Gulp | KnockoutJS | Small Business Owner

# **Projects**

My Website 2018

- Used HTML, JavaScript/Jquery, Bootstrap, KnockoutJs and CSS to make a resumè web site.
- Practical application of the skills learned from Udacity Front End Web Developer Progam.

## Neighborhood Map for Udacity

2018

- A challenging project integrating various API's, AJAX, JavaScript and KnockoutJS framework.
- Created a Google maps page showing POI and retrieving reviews and street views of locations

#### Frogger clone for Udacity

2018

- An interesting introduction to Object Oriented Programing.
- Learned to read, understand and modify existing code while developing and integrating my own.

# **Experience**

Driver | Airgas | Star, MS

7/2008 - Current

- Driving and managing multiple deliveries a week for over 9 years successfully and safely.
- Filling in at other locations when needed, providing a model later termed "fast team" by corporate.

#### Owner/Operator | Peterson Transportation | Seminary, MS

4/2003 - 6/2008

- Started my own trucking company.
- Managed leasing, loads, scheduling, bookkeeping and DOT compliance.

#### Manager/Driver | Sanderson Farms| Collins, MS

11/1993 - 10/1999

- Managed a spray crew of 4.
- Became a driver to help get the live haul division started and substituted for managers needing time off.

## **Education**

#### Udacity | Online

Front End Web Developer Nano-Degree

2018

## O'Reilly School of Technology | Online

Linux Sysems Administration

2015

Introduction to Database Administration

2014

## University of Phoenix | Online

CompTIA A+ and Networking +

2014